

# Ruben Caliandro

Technical Artist, Game Programmer, Full-Stack Web Developer

CONTACT

Date of Birth June 7, 1990

Email ruben.caliandro@gmail.com

Phone (+39) 333 736 8333

Location Torino, IT

PROFILES

Github https://github.com/chosko

Linkedin https://www.linkedin.com/in/rubencaliandro/en

Personal http://chosko.com

I have a strong interest in Computer Graphics and Videogames since I was 15. I work as Techical Artist and Game Programmer at Tiny Bull Studios, an indie game developer based in Torino (Italy). I make real-time visual effects and I am specialized in writing shaders for Virtual Reality.

ABOUT

I am also Web Developer since 2010. I worked in companies located in Italy (Torino) and USA (Sunnyvale, CA).

I graduated with a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science in 2012 and a Master's degree in Virtual Reality in 2017, both with the score of 110/100 with honors

# WORK EXPERIENCE

♥ TURIN, ITALY

□ DEC, 2016 — PRESENT

**②** 1 YEAR 7 MONTHS

# Technical Artist, Game Programmer at Tiny Bull Studios srl:

(http://www.tinybullstudios.com/)

Visual Effects and Game Programming

- Shader Programming and Optimisation
- Particle Systems and Post-Processing
- Making the effects support Virtual Reality
- Main Technologies: Unity, C#, ShaderLab, CG/HLSL/GLSL, Oculus, Vive, PlayStation s4

♥ TURIN, ITALY

■ MAY, 2015 — SEP, 2017

② 2 YEARS 5 MONTHS

Full-stack Web Developer at Tandù srl: (http://tandu.it)

Project Management and Full-Stack Development.

- Main technologies: Node.js/Express, Ruby on Rails, AngularJS, AWS, Docker, CircleCI

Sunnyvale, CA, USA

**②** 3 MONTHS

#### Front-end Web Developer at Eversnap: (http://www.geteversnap.com/home.html)

Front-end Development

- Web application development (front-end) using AngularJS
- Project architecture refactoring
- Automatic tools and CI with git, GruntJS and Fabric

♥ TURIN, ITALY

② 1 YEAR

#### Web Application Developer at MyTable:

Full-Stack Development

- Web Application Design and Development (both Client and Server-Side).
- Design and Development of some Ruby Gems (and Rails Engines).
- Skills: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, MySQL, UML

**♥** TURIN, ITALY

② 2 YEARS 10 MONTHS

# Web Application Developer at Condominioitalia Editrice:

Web Development

- Web Application Design, Development and Graphics.
- Private Network and PCs Maintenance.
- Recording and Editing of the online news 'TG del Condominio'.
- Skills: PHP, MySQL, (X)HTML, Javascript.

# VOLUNTEER

② 3 YEARS 9 MONTHS

### Film Projectionist, Cinema Teatro Cuore:

35mm Film Projections.

- Film assembling and deassembling.
- Security checks.
- Film projections and manual changeovers with two Cinemeccanica Victoria 8.

### **EDUCATION**

Score: 110/110 with

# Università degli studi di Torino - Computer Science Department

Master of Science: Computer Graphics, Virtual Reality and Multimedia

- MFN0978 Virtual Reality Systems 30/30 with honors
- MFN0947 Multimedia Database 28/30
- MFN0972 Digital Image Processing and Artificial Vision 30/30
- MFN0970 Physics for Virtual Reality 30/30
- MFN0942 Artificial Intelligence 30/30
- MFN0973 3D Graphics Modeling 30/30 with honors
- MFN0962 Numerical Methods 20/30
- MFN0960 Concurrent Models and Distributed Algorithms 30/30
- MFN0963 English II Approved
- MFN0961 Information Theory 27/30
- MFN0949 Cognitive Systems 30/30
- MFN0951 Digital Audio and Music Processing 30/30 with honors
- MFN0977 Neural Networks 30/30

Thesis: Visual Effects for Real-Time Stereoscopic Rendering

# 

Score: 110/110 WITH

# Università degli studi di Torino - Computer Science Department

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science (Networks)

Thesis: Spam Analysis tools

## High School P. Gobetti

High School: Science

Thesis: Mathematics applied to 3D Computer Graphics Programming

# **PROJECTS**

□ DEC, 2016 — PRESENT

### Blind (https://www.tinybullstudios.com/games/blind/) — VR Game

Blind is a narrative-driven psychological thriller for virtual reality where the player is blind and must explore their surroundings using echolocation.

- Keywords: Virtual Reality, Puzzle Game, Unity, Oculus, SteamVR, PlayStation VR

### ₩ SEP, 2016

### Feed The Troll (https://risingpixel.itch.io/feed-the-troll) — Videogame

A multi-player multi-device videogame, with an unconventional gameplay based on real communication between the players.

- Winner of the MTV Mega Game Jam 2016 @ MTV Digital Days 2016
- Keywords: 2D Game, Asymmetrical co-op multiplayer, Unity

#### 

# Tron Lightcycles (https://github.com/chosko/lightcycle) — 3D Model

A 3D scene representing two Lightcycles from the movie 'Tron Legacy'. Modeled with Blender and shaded with OSL.

- Keywords: 3D Modeling, Blender, Shaders, OSL

### 

### 

Lazy is the video game who doesn't want to be played. The game is not willing to play with you and it will try everything to make you quit as soon as possible.

- Keywords: 3D Game, First Person, Unity3D, Cross-Platform

#### 

# 

Strategy game made in 48h for the Alpha Game Jam in San Francisco. Defend your home and destroy the enemy hive or defeat all the enemy bugs

- Keywords: 2D Game, Strategy, Unity3D, Cross-Platform

₩ Nov, 2013

ScrollCraft (http://www.windowsphone.com/it-it/store/app/scrollcraft/8f7c61d3-9f2b-4092-b02d-212519f872d8) — Videogame

Developed in 48hours, during the international Indie Speed Run 2013. It is an endless runner featuring the theme and the element assigned to the team: Speed and Scroll.

- Keywords: 2D Game, MonoGame, C#, Cross-Platform
- Team members: Roberto Pesando, Stefano Nada, Stefano Ordine and I

∰ JUL, 2013

AMCG (https://github.com/psicomante/aamcg) — Videogame

Another Multiplayer Cuboids Game: a shared-screen party game where characters are controlled with smartphones.

- Keywords: Unity, C#, GLSL, Network, Multiplayer
- Team members: Roberto Pesando and I

**Minesweeper3D** (https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/8771146/Minesweeper3D.zip) — Videogame

A 3D version of the classic Minesweeper made in 48h. The puzzle is really hard to solve: the average resolution time for a 10x10x15 grid is about an hour.

- Keywords: 3D Game, Puzzle Game, XNA, C#

Continuum (https://github.com/xteamdimension/continuum-arena) — Videogame

A 2D space shooter for Windows Phone made with XNA. Collecting "tachyon streams" you are enabled to rewind and warp the time.

- Keywords: 2D Game, Space Shooter, XNA, Windows Phone, Time Travel.
- Team members: Stefano Nada, Stefano Ordine and I

### Mathematics applied to 3D Computer-Graphics programming

(https://github.com/Chosko/high-school-thesis) — 3D Simulation, High School Thesis

A 3D Simulation of the Solar System built with C# and DirectX, presented as a thesis demo at the end of the High School

- Keywords: 3D Simulation, DirectX, C#, HLSL shaders, High School Thesis

AWARDS

 MTV Mega Game Jam @ MTV Digital Days 2016

Won with "Feed The Troll", an asymmetrical co-op multiplayer made with Unity.

 Alpha Game Jam 2014, San Francisco

Won with "Battle Bugs", a strategy 2D game made with Unity.

THIRD PLACE

☐ FEB 23, 2015

Global Game Jam 2015, Turin Competition

Won with "Lazy", the game who doesn't want to be played. Made with Unity.

Languages

Italian Native speaker

English Professional working proficiency

Interests

Guitar: Electric Guitar, Classical Guitar
Film Projectionism: 35mm film projections

Rubik's Cube: up to 4x4x4